<img src="/public/posts/posterFilmsPR1.jpg" />
<h2>Intro</h2>
<p>
So we love what we do and love watching movies. Aside from procrastinating and laughing at nothing, media can actually teach you a few helpful things. Thus, we came up with a few films that contribute heavily to your overall understanding of marketing/PR/sales. To assess the dramatics as well as helpfulness of the material we came up with a grading system, in which 1 implies <i>maudlin</i> and 5 means <i>utilitarian</i>. This grading system entails an analysis of the special tactics employed in every movie that is being used to teach a certain lesson. 
</p>

<preview/>


<div class="container-fluid">

<div class="row">
    <h2>Wag the Dog</h2>
    <div class="col-xs-3" style="padding-left:0px">
        <img src="/public/posts/wg.png" style="width:100%" />
    </div>
    <div class="col-xs-7">
        <h3>Utilitarity: 5</h3>
        <p>
            Well… It is more about politics, and the heavy artillery of PR. <br/>
            The politics has it`s own informational space and reason for a certain type of information etc. Except for this time the scale is colossal and the attention of the user is of utmost importance.
        It actually helps you to figure out how the PR works. It reveals the basis of how the viral marketing came about.   
        </p>
        <p>
            The film inspires you to think about the eternal glory that could be borne out of managing the public attention.
        </p>
    </div>
</div>

<div class="row">
    <h2>Thank You for Smoking</h2>
    <div class="col-xs-3" style="padding-left:0px">
        <img src="/public/posts/sm.png" style="width:100%" />
    </div>
    <div class="col-xs-7"> 
        <h3>Utilitarity: 4</h3>
        <p>
            This is about selling hard. Do you get it that you sell death and sell it well? Just like in season 1 episode 1 of <i>MadMen</i>, which is called <i>Smoke gets in Your Eye</i>. In the episode, the sales people pitch the idea that a particular brand of cigarettes <i>is toasted</i>a, thus alleviating the anxiety of damaging your health because of the fleur of the veil-like smoke that did get in the people’s eye. As per the obvious pun and the discussion of the <i>MadMen</i>, we will get to it in our next post.  
        </p>
        <p>
            Getting back to the business of <i>Thank You for Smoking</i>, it is a pretty deep movie as it touche some pretty deep social and political questions that should be considered when carrying out a marketing campaign. This film does require some thinking afterwards. 
        </p>
        <p>
            The movie does call for a good consideration of product placement, negotiation and corporate strategies. To show how things work, the movie puts the protagonist in a situation in which he faces the seemingly silly questions of his son, but then has to respond with a lucid, smart explanation about them. And hey, this is about some serious business! As well as a good marketing strategy. 
        </p>
    </div>
</div>

<div class="row">
    <h2>Joneses</h2>
    <div class="col-xs-3" style="padding-left:0px">
        <img src="/public/posts/jn.png" style="width:100%" />
    </div>
    <div class="col-xs-7">
        <h3>Utilitarity: 2</h3>
        <p>
            This is a melodramatic movie, yes. It tells you the story of direct sales and product placement. And there is a difference between this an actual hard core marketing. It also tells you the story of sales referral and the gist of the ripple effect. It gives the actual names to the party that sells and the party that actually buys (an easy example illustrating this is how video bloggers make money).
        </p>
    </div>
</div>

<div class="row">
    <h2>Jerry Maguire</h2>
    <div class="col-xs-3" style="padding-left:0px">
        <img src="/public/posts/jm.png" style="width:100%"  /> 
    </div>
    <div class="col-xs-7">
        <h3>Utilitarity: 1</h3>
        <p>
            It is interesting in its own right: selling ads as well as signing up contracts with sportsmen. To quote from Jerry Maguire: “unless you love everybody you can’t sell anybody.” The movie gives good examples of B2B sales and illustrates a marketplace in which you need to find sportsmen and pair them up with their agents. 
        </p>
    </div>
</div>

<h2>Honorable mentions</h2>
<p>
    This is not a full list, I just picked what I found to be of interest. There are links below for you to check out to get more information:
    <ul>
        <li>http://www.businessinsider.com/top-10-best-pr-movies-and-a-few-great-public-relations-tv-shows-2011-9</li>
        <li>http://www.teamlewis.com/us/insights/articles/10-must-see-movies-about-pr-marketing-and-advertising</li>
    </ul>
</p>

</div>